Time flies, or so they say.
人们常说，时光飞逝。
No matter where you are, humans are constantly measuring and checking time.
无论你身在何处，人类不断地计量和查看时间。
Some of us are good at it – planning and doing things way ahead of time - while others are always trying to beat the clock and do things at the eleventh hour.
我们中的一些人很擅长这一点——提前规划和做事——而另一些人总是试图赶时间，在最后一刻才做事。
And that’s only if you’re on time.
而这还只是在你准时的情况下。
What about if you are behind time?
如果你迟到了呢？
Tardiness can be serious.
迟到可能是很严重的问题。
If you were one minute late for work, would you resign?
如果你上班迟到了一分钟，你会辞职吗？
It may sound extreme to many of us, but that is exactly what occurred in the UK upper chamber of parliament, the House of Lords, in January 2018.
这对我们很多人来说可能听起来很极端，但这正是2018年1月在英国议会上议院发生的事情。
International development minister Lord Bates arrived one minute late, and, as a result, was unable to answer a scheduled question.
国际发展部大臣贝茨勋爵（Lord Bates）迟到了一分钟，结果无法回答一个预定的问题。
Instead of trying to make up for lost time, as many might do, he resigned on the spot.
他没有像很多人可能会做的那样试图抓紧时间，而是当场辞职。
He apologised for his discourtesy and stated that he was ashamed.
他为自己的失礼道歉，并表示自己很羞愧。
His resignation, though, was not accepted by the UK prime minister.
不过，英国首相没有接受他的辞职。
So, how late is too late?
那么，迟到多晚算非常晚呢？
Many cultures take punctuality very seriously, whereas others seem to accept lagging behind as just the normal way of things.
许多文化非常重视守时，而其他文化似乎把落后（迟到）当作正常的事情来接受。
Members of the BBC from various different cultures were asked about the concept of timekeeping in their native countries and responded with a raft of answers.
来自不同文化的英国广播公司（BBC）员工被问及他们本国的守时观念，他们给出了许多答案。
BBC employees from Latin America, Rwanda and Sri Lanka said that there are more flexible attitudes to timekeeping in their cultures.
来自拉丁美洲、卢旺达和斯里兰卡的BBC员工表示，在他们的文化中，人们对守时的态度更加灵活。
In Latin America, things may happen five minutes, 20 minutes, an hour or even two after they were planned.
在拉丁美洲，事情可能会在计划时间之后的五分钟、二十分钟、一个小时甚至两个小时才发生。
Whereas, in Sri Lanka, lateness is a part of the daily routine.
而在斯里兰卡，迟到是日常生活的一部分。
This is because of poor infrastructure and heavy traffic conditions.
这是因为落后的基础设施和严重的交通拥堵。
In Rwanda, those who attend to deadlines with rigid timekeeping are said to be ‘like a typical European’.
在卢旺达，那些严格遵守时间期限的人被说成是“像典型的欧洲人”。
This is in a place where it is not unusual to arrive at 11am for a meeting which started at nine.
在这个地方，上午九点开始的会议，十一点才到也不是什么不寻常的事。
On the other hand, German and Japanese employees mentioned a stricter adherence to time.
另一方面，德国和日本的员工提到了更严格地遵守时间。
In Japan, it is common to make an effort to arrive with time to spare for an appointment.
在日本，人们通常会尽量提前一会到达约会地点。
Those who arrived at the stroke of nine to a meeting starting at nine a.m. would be considered late.
上午九点开始会议，九点整到达的人会被认为迟到了。
In Germany, however, if a dinner party were to begin at eight, a person who had arrived five minutes prior, may walk around the block to ensure that they arrive at eight on the dot.
然而，在德国，如果一个晚宴八点开始，一个提前五分钟到达的人可能会在街区周围四处走走，以确保自己八点准时到达。
It seems that the answer is subjective, and what is considered acceptable is based on culture.
似乎答案是主观的，什么是可以接受的是基于文化的。
That said, if you don’t mind waiting, it might be best to attend your appointments in good time.
话虽如此，如果你不介意等待，最好还是适时去赴约。
And if the worst comes to the worst, remember the old English proverb. Better late than never.
如果情况糟糕到了极点，记住那句古老的英语谚语：迟到总比不到好。